Contact

khalifa.deena82@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/deena-bsn-rn (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare

Hospitals

Electronic Medical Record (EMR)

Certifications

Registered Nurse

Honors-Awards

Cum Laude

Cum Laude

Cum Laude

Deena Khalifa

BSN, RN, PHN

San Francisco Bay Area

Summary

Infusion RN at Pacific Frontier Medical; in addition to accessing IV peripheral lines and administering infusions I also perform venipunctures and blood draws from PICC lines and ports, process blood specimens, change PICC line dressings, access ports, mix/prepare medications to be administered, and assist with other administrative office duties. BSN Graduate of SFSU and certified Public Health Nurse. I have over seven years of progressive work experience within healthcare settings, including Certified Medical Assisting (CCMA April 2013 - May 2018). I am well-rounded in both clinical and administrative patient care, and strive to provide optimal, safe, effective, and efficient nursing with an emphasis on patient education while encountering a variety of medical situations.

All clinical rotations passed and completed as follows: Pediatrics at UCSF Benioff Children's Hospital Oakland, Public Health and Psychiatry with the County of San Mateo, Labor/Delivery at Washington Hospital, Fundamentals of Nursing at Laguna Honda Hospital Skilled Nursing Facility, Med-Surg and Senior Preceptorship within the Med-Surg-Ortho unit at Sequoia Hospital.

Proficient in Epic, Cerner, and Elations Electronic Medical Records and certified in Basic Life Support (BLS), Advanced Cardiovascular Life Support (ACLS), Pediatric Advanced Life Support (PALS), and NIH Stroke Scale.

Experience

Pacific Frontier Medical
Registered Nurse
March 2019 - Present (1 year 5 months)

Accessing peripheral lines for IV infusions, administering infusions through peripheral, port, and PICC lines, monitoring patients throughout infusions, addressing adverse reactions and reporting to physicians. Performing

PICC line dressing changes and accessing ports while maintaining sterile technique throughout; notetaking and informing physicians of abnormalities at PICC line or port sites. Mixing and preparing medications for infusions, including antibiotics and nutritional IVs; ensuring correct calculations and drip rates via gravity drip. Performing venipunctures as well as blood draws from ports and PICC lines, processing blood and urine specimens while adhering to specimen collection instructions for laboratory pick-up and/or mail out. Administrative duties such as: Providing patient call-backs in a timely manner, relaying advise, follow-ups, alerting physicians of critical lab values and/or urgent messages, calling in prescriptions, mailing appropriate supplements, documenting all patient calls and procedures with attention to detail. Maintaining inventory, ordering new medications and/or supplements when appropriate, discarding expired medications appropriately, ensuring biohazard and sharps waste is disposed of properly

Sutter Health - Palo Alto Medical Foundation 3 years 2 months

Certified Medical Assistant March 2012 - March 2013 (1 year 1 month) Redwood City, CA

Participated in the daily running of outpatient vascular surgery practice as a Medical Assistant/Department Coordinator. Prepared clients for venous ablations, assisted vascular surgeon throughout procedure, provided preand post-procedure patient education, measured vital signs of clients and notified surgeon of abnormal findings in a timely manner, ensured outpatient procedure room and exam rooms were sanitized, stocked, and appropriately set up prior to rooming clients, utilized Epic software to document clinical data, record correspondence, and maintain updated patient information, managed rooming and client flow including pre- and post-visit preparation, greeted clients upon arrival, answered telephone and scheduled office visit appointments, rescheduled and cancelled appointments when applicable, ensured timely, quality patient care to meet workflow needs, reviewed surgeon's schedule for accuracy and compliance with organizational policies and unimpeded patient flow.

Patient Service Representative February 2010 - March 2012 (2 years 2 months) Burlingame, CA

Scheduled appointments and checked patients in-and-out of outpatient cardiology practice. Maintained effective communication and coordination

with colleagues sharing patient check-in functions, brought discrepancies within schedule to the attention of supervisor, suggested methods to resolve discrepancies, retrieved messages, provided call-backs, and forwarded calls to appropriate members of team when applicable, communicated effectively with supervisor and colleagues to adjust schedule according to availability of clinicians. Expanded duties beyond scheduling by: Liaising with insurance providers on behalf of clients, conducting pre-authorizations for clients under Medi-Cal and HMO insurances, resolving discrepancies within authorizations to ensure patients had proper coverage for appointments, performing data entry and documentation in Epic software.

Building Technology Consultants, Inc. Executive Assistant March 2007 - August 2008 (1 year 6 months) Arlington Heights, Illinois

Acted as Executive Assistant to Principal of forensic engineering firm with award-winning projects. Answered incoming calls, took clear and concise messages for staff, greeted client visitors, maintained conference rooms and waiting area, booked all components of travel arrangements and managed schedule for Principal of company, liaised between Principal, engineers, and clients, drafted proposals for clients, created detailed templates using Microsoft PowerPoint, Word and Excel spreadsheets.

Starbucks
Shift Supervisor
June 2006 - February 2007 (9 months)
Boston, Massachusetts

Promoted from Barista to Shift Supervisor of busy Starbucks location in downtown Boston. In addition to preparing drinks and food for customers; supervised up to five baristas per shift, trained new employees, anticipated store and customer needs, communicated pertinent store and employee information to manager, followed all cash management and cash register policies, conducted proper store opening and closing, addressed concerns among patrons and employees, ensured work environment and conditions were safe and sanitary for operation.

4Cs of Alameda County Secretary October 2003 - January 2006 (2 years 4 months) Hayward, CA Performed bilingual-Spanish secretarial duties for non-profit family resource agency and aided families in obtaining access to affordable, quality childcare by connecting them with providers. Answered incoming calls and directed calls to appropriate staff members, provided information to clients about services over the telephone and in person, collaborated with CalWorks department to ensure payments to providers were recorded and mailed in a timely manner, maintained waiting areas and conference rooms, assisted Executive and Deputy Directors in drafting proposals for grant funds, and assisted with various projects for the Nutrition Program and Resource/Referral Department.

Sequoia Medical Assocites (via Judy Madrigal and Associates)
Appointment Scheduler
March 2001 - June 2003 (2 years 4 months)
Redwood City, CA

Scheduled appointments for Internal Medicine practice, retrieved telephone messages and returned calls to schedule appointments in a timely manner, maintained demographic and insurance information of patients while checking eligibility, forwarded non-appointment messages to appropriate healthcare staff while ensuring urgent calls were marked and addressed accordingly, cancelled and rescheduled appointments as needed, collaborated with Office Manager to adjust schedule as needed by physicians.

Burlingame Family Health Clerical Assistant April 1998 - June 2000 (2 years 3 months) Burlingame, CA

Part-time position filing patient charts alphabetically, preparing charts and superbills for next-day appointments, filing medical documents into patient charts and checking for accurate filing.

Education

San Francisco State University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Registered Nursing/Registered

Nurse · (2013 - 2018)

Skyline College
Associate of Science - AS, Allied Health and Medical Assisting
Services · (2013 - 2016)

Heald College-Hayward

Associate of Science - AS, Medical/Clinical Assistant · (2003 - 2005)